chatango.com 2019-03-08

# Chatango Terms of Use

This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information we gather when you use the Chatango service, as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard it. Chatango is privately owned and operated by Chatango LLC (referred to herein as "we" or "us".)

The following principles apply to the personally identifying information we ask for and that you provide. "Personally identifying information" is information that individually identifies you, such as your email address.

**Data collection**  
To register for Chatango, you are asked to provide your email address. You are also asked to choose a personal screen name and password. You may also provide optional information, such as your gender, country or US zip code, age and photo. We do not collect your exact birthdate, only your age when you create your profile. 

**Cookies**  
When you login or send messages in Chatango, we use cookies and similar technologies to store your session authentication, your messages and your preferences data on your computer. From this data, only your session authentication cookie is transmitted to Chatango servers. This session data is only used for security purposes, such as user authentication and spam prevention, and is not shared with any third parties. You can delete your browser cookies to remove your Chatango data from your computer or use your browser in Incognito mode to prevent this data from being stored. 

**IP addresses**  
We do store IP addresses of all incoming connections to Chatango servers. This information is only stored for network security purposes such as preventing spam, denial of service attacks or intrusion. When a user sends a message to a Chatango Group, the IP address of the sender is recorded and displayed to the group owner and to the group moderators created by the group owner, so that the group owner and moderators can ban the sender from the group. 

**Private messages**  
Your real-time private messages sent when your conversation party has their Chatango messenger open are not stored on Chatango servers. They are only stored on the devices of the users that participated in the conversation. 

**Chatango app**  
When available, we store the model, operating system version, and hardware serial number of the device where Chatango apps are installed. This information is stored strictly for security (moderation and spam prevention) and crash debugging purposes. It is not shared with any Chatango users or third parties. The appropriate permissions to access this information are requested by Google Play Store and Apple App Store when the Chatango app is installed and used. 

**Payment Information**  
We store payment information (credit card type, card holder's name, credit card expiration date, PayPal account email) for all payments and donations made to Chatango. Credit card numbers are not stored on our servers. This information is used exclusively for security purposes, such as preventing fraudulent payments. It is only shared with our payment processor to facilitate the payment. 

**Information sharing**

  1. We do not sell your personally identifying information to other companies or individuals. We may share such information in the following limited circumstances: 
    1. We have your explicit revokable consent. 
    2. We provide such information to trusted businesses or persons for the sole purpose of processing personally identifying information on our behalf. When this is done, it is subject to agreements that oblige those parties to process such information only on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 
    3. We conclude that we are required by law or have a good faith belief that access, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Chatango, its users or the public. 
  2. If you choose to provide your age, gender, town, country, photographs or videos, we may share this information with other Chatango users as a part of the Chatango service. You can delete this information by editing your profile or by deleting your Chatango account. 

**Third Party Advertising**   

* We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) and [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

**Information security**

  1. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. We do not store your passwords, or credit card numbers, we only store their HMAC hash. 
  2. We restrict access to your personally identifying information to employees who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. 

**Use of the Chatango messenger**

  1. We do not monitor communications made by users using the Chatango messenger. 
  2. We may securely store your communications for archiving purposes. These stored communications may only be accessible through Chatango's features by the parties who participated in communications. 
  3. Your live private messages sent when the receiving party is online are only stored on the computers of the parties that participated in the conversation. They are not currently stored on Chatango servers. You can delete this chat history from your devices by clearing your browser storage or your app storage. 
  4. We do not control the use of the Chatango messenger or the parties with whom you may choose to communicate. You should not share your personal information with any third party. 

**Changes to this Policy** Please note this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Any new version or updates will be posted on this page. If you have any additional questions, please contact us. 

Apr 27, 2018
